
const q20251027EnsimmainenKoe = [

  {
    question: "Olohuone",
    answers: {
      a: "A livingroom",
      b: "A bathroom",
      c: "An livingroom",
      d: "A museum"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "Ravintola",
    answers: {
      a: "A hall",
      b: "An airport",
      c: "A restaurant",
      d: "An attic"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "Hän ei ole koulussa",
    answers: {
      a: "He not cool",
      b: "She is in the school",
      c: "He isn't in cool",
      d: "She is not in the school"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: "Tall",
    answers: {
      a: "Vahva",
      b: "Pitkä",
      c: "Nopea",
      d: "Talli"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Sorry is he in a zoo?",
    answers: {
      a: "Anteeksi onko hän eläintarhassa?",
      b: "Anteeksi onko hän keittiössä?",
      c: "Anteeksi onko hän ullakolla?",
      d: "Onko hän kirjastossa?"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "Hän on elokuvissa",
    answers: {
      a: "She is at the zoo",
      b: "He is behind the sofa",
      c: "He is at the cinema",
      d: "He's at the cinama"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "Tuoli on pöydän takana",
    answers: {
      a: "A chair is in table",
      b: "A chair is at the table",
      c: "A chair is behind a table",
      d: "An chair is behind the table"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "Quiet",
    answers: {
      a: "Äänekäs",
      b: "Nopea",
      c: "Hiljainen",
      d: "Kuuma"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "A loud mouse is in the attic",
    answers: {
      a: "Hiljainen hiiri on eteisessä",
      d: "Hiiri on aatelisten salissa",
      c: "Äänekäs hiiri on ullakolla",
      d: "Äänekäs hiiri on ullakon alla"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "Pallo on keittiössä",
    answers: {
      a: "A ball is in the kitchen",
      b: "A ball is at the kitchen",
      c: "A ball is on the kitchen",
      d: "A hall is in the kitchen"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  }
];



const q2025Kappale4Ja5JaVahan8ia = [
  {
    question: "Come here Anni",
    answers: {
      a: "Mene Anni",
      b: "Katso Anni",
      c: "Tule tänne Anni",
      d: "Ole van Anni"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "Kysy Wilmalta! Hän on kiltti",
    answers: {
      a: "Ask Wilma she is nice",
      b: "Ask Wilma he is noce",
      c: "Aks Wilma she is noce",
      d: "Ask Wilma she nice"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "I listen Venny",
    answers: {
      a: "Minä kuuntelen Vennyä",
      b: "Minä kuulin Vennyä",
      c: "Kuuntelemalla tarkasti olen kuin Venny",
      d: "Minä kysyn Vennyltä"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "Go help Nipsu",
    answers: {
      a: "Meinasin hellittää",
      b: "Mene auttamaan Nipsua",
      c: "Mennään, auttamaan Nipsuja",
      d: "Menin auttelemaan Nipsua"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Puhua",
    answers: {
      a: "Ask",
      b: "Think",
      c: "Laugh",
      d: "Talk"

    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: "Nenna _____ hopschotch",
    answers: {
      a: "likes",
      b: "old",
      c: "rides",
      d: "smiles"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "Ajattelen sulkapalloa Emmi",
    answers: {
      a: "I think badminton Emmi",
      b: "I think chess Emmi",
      c: "I think table tennis Emmi",
      d: "I think tennis Emmi"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "Wilma _____ at the video game",
    answers: {
      a: "look",
      b: "go",
      c: "ask",
      d: "come"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "Felix on äänekäs ja hän ei ole 20",
    answers: {
      a: "Felix is not loud and he is not twenty",
      b: "Felix is loud and he is not twenty",
      c: "Felix loudy and twelve",
      d: "Felix is loud and he is not twelve"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Chess is quiet sport",
    answers: {
      a: "Shakki on hieno urheilulaji",
      b: "Shakki on hiljainen urheilulaji",
      c: "Rintauinti on hilainen urheilulaji",
      d: "Kroolaus on hiljainen urheilulaji"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  }
];


const q2025Kappale4Ja5JaEnnenSitaTaas = [
  {
    question: "Kuuntele Ramboa",
    answers: {
      a: "Listen to Rambo",
      b: "Hear Ramboa",
      c: "Litsen to Rambo",
      d: "Look to Rambo"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "Hugo is a young dog",
    answers: {
      a: "Hugo on hauska koira",
      b: "Hugo on nuori koira",
      c: "Hugo on nuori dogi",
      d: "Hugo on pieni koira"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Moona ei pidä Hugo koirasta",
    answers: {
      a: "Moona not likes Hugo dog",
      b: "Moona doesn't like Hugo dog",
      c: "Moona does not liek Hugo dog",
      d: "Moona does not lick dog"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Eric likes floorball and table tennis",
    answers: {
      a: "Eric tykkää pingiksestä ja lentopallosta",
      b: "Eric rakastaa salibandystä ja pingiksestä",
      c: "Eric tykkää pöytätenniksestä ja teniksestä",
      d: "Eric tykkää salibandystä ja pingiksestä"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: "Katso Calypsoa, se on Ericin",
    answers: {
      a: "Shout Calypso, it's Eric's",
      b: "Look at Calypso, it's Eric's",
      c: "Looks Calypso, it is Eric",
      d: "Nice Calypso, Eric likes it"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Go and shout Calypso Moona",
    answers: {
      a: "Mene ja huuda Calypsoa Moona",
      b: "Mene ja ääntele Calypso Moona",
      c: "Huuda isosti Calypsoa Moona",
      d: "Elehdi äänekkäästi Calypsoa Moona"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  },
  {
    question: "Anni tule nopeasti, kuuntele Eric",
    answers: {
      a: "Anni come now, listen Eric",
      b: "Anni come fast, ask help",
      c: "Anni come fast, ask Eric",
      d: "Anni come fast, listen Eric"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: "Rölli kuuntele ja auta Tuulia",
    answers: {
      a: "Tuuli help and listen Rölli",
      b: "Rölli listen and help Tuuli",
      c: "Rölli listen and think Tuuli",
      d: "Rölli is and listen Tuuli"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Roosa play card",
    answers: {
      a: "Roosa pelaa karttingia",
      b: "Roosa pelaa herttapeliä",
      c: "Roosa pelaa lentopalloa",
      d: "Roosa pelaa korttipeliä"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  }
]

const q2025Kappale4Ja5JaEnnenSitaLisaa = [
  {
    question: "Smile Moona",
    answers: {
      a: "Kiirehdi Moona",
      b: "Ilmeile Moona",
      c: "Iloitse Moona",
      d: "Hymyile Moona"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: "Help small hamster under the table Siiri",
    answers: {
      a: "Aina kannattaa auttaa hamsteria Siiri",
      b: "Pöytä ja hamsteri ovat hyvä pieni pari Siiri",
      c: "Auta hamsteria pöydän päältä Siiri",
      d: "Auta pientä hamsteria pöydän alla Siiri"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: "Nikita on nopea Rocky hidas Star ei ole hidas",
    answers: {
      a: "Nikita is fat Rocky is young Star is not slow",
      b: "Nikita isn't fast Rocky isn't young Star is slow",
      c: "Nikita is fast Rocky is slow Star isn't slow",
      d: "Nikita is fast Rocky is fast Star isn't slow"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "Nikita ei tule hän leikkii piiloleikkiä",
    answers: {
      a: "Nikita does not come she in strong",
      b: "Nikita does not come she plays hide-and-seek",
      c: "ikita does not come she plays hide-seek",
      d: "ikita does not come she plays hide-and-seek"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Anni ajattelee Ramboa Rambo on nuori ja nopea",
    answers: {
      a: "Anni likes Rambo Rambo is young and slow",
      b: "Anni tinks Rambo Rambo is young and fat",
      c: "Anni thinks Rambo Rambo is young and fast",
      d: "Anni thinks Rambo Rambo is young and last"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "Mutta Star on vahva ajatteletko että Star voi hypätä esteitä?",
    answers: {
      a: "But Star is fast do you think Star can jump obstacles?",
      b: "But Star is strong do you think Star can jump obstacles?",
      c: "But Star is stron do you think Star can jump obstacles?",
      d: "But Tar is strong do you think Star may jump obstacles?"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Kyllä ja Star on pitkä ja alle 12",
    answers: {
      a: "Yes and Star is small and under 12",
      b: "Yes and Star is tall and under 12",
      c: "Yes and Star is tal and uber 12",
      d: "Yes Star under 12 and tall"
    },
    correctAnswer: "b"
  },
  {
    question: "Nikita on nopea Rocky on nuori Star ei ole hidas",
    answers: {
      a: "Nikita is fast Rocky is young Star is not alone",
      b: "Nikita isn't fast Rocky isn't young Star is slow",
      c: "Nikita is fast Rocky is young Star isn't slow",
      d: "Nikita is fast Rocky is fast Star isn't slow"
    },
    correctAnswer: "c"
  },
  {
    question: "Siiri pidätkö shakista?",
    answers: {
      a: "Siiri do you like badminton?",
      b: "Siiri don't like chess?",
      c: "Siiri do like chess?",
      d: "Siiri do you like chess?"
    },
    correctAnswer: "d"
  },
  {
    question: "En se on vanha peli pidän pingiksestä",
    answers: {
      a: "No it's an old game I like table tennis",
      b: "No it is an old game I like badminton",
      c: "No it is an old game I shout floorball",
      d: "No it's an old game I like tag"
    },
    correctAnswer: "a"
  }
];

const q2025Unit2Kappale4 =
  [{ "question": "Siiri tanssitaan", "answers": { "a": "Siiri come dance", "b": "Siiri let's dance", "c": "Siiri get dance", "d": "Siiri go dance" }, "correctAnswer": "b" }, { "question": "Pystytkö sinä tanssimaan myös Emmi?", "answers": { "a": "Can you skate too Emmi?", "b": "Can you ski too Emmi?", "c": "Can you dance too Emmi?", "d": "Can you play the piano too Emmi?" }, "correctAnswer": "c" }, { "question": "En mutta voin katsoa kun tanssit", "answers": { "a": "No but I can shout you dance", "b": "No but I can help you dance", "c": "No but I can listen you dance", "d": "No but I can look you dance" }, "correctAnswer": "d" }, { "question": "Minä nauran mutta sinä Emmi hymyile", "answers": { "a": "I smile but you Emmi talk", "b": "I listen but you Emmmi smile", "c": "I laugh but you Emmi smile", "d": "I laugh but you Emmi ask" }, "correctAnswer": "c" }, { "question": "Kiva viikonloppu Emmi pelaa jääkiekkoa", "answers": { "a": "Nice weekend Emmi plays guitar", "b": "Nice geekend Emmi plays floorbal", "c": "Nice weekend Emmi plays ice hockey", "d": "Nice weekend Emmi skates" }, "correctAnswer": "c" }, { "question": "Minä pidän myös jääkiekosta, pitääkö Eric?", "answers": { "a": "I talk ice hockey too does Eric?", "b": "I like ice hockey too does Eric?", "c": "I play ice hockey too does Eric?", "d": "I play hockey too do Eric?" }, "correctAnswer": "b" }, { "question": "Ajattele piirtämistä se on hidas urheilulaji", "answers": { "a": "Listen drawing it is slow sport", "b": "Shout drawing it is fast sport", "c": "Think drawing it is slow sport", "d": "Think gnawling it is slow sport" }, "correctAnswer": "c" }, { "question": "Emmi piirretään paperi on pöydän päällä", "answers": { "a": "Emmi go draw the paper is behind the table", "b": "Emmi let's draw the paper is on top of the table", "c": "Emmi come to draw the paper is under the table", "d": "Emmi come to think the paper is on the table" }, "correctAnswer": "b" }, { "question": "Kiitos mutta ajattelen kirjoittavani", "answers": { "a": "Thank but I look I read", "b": "Thank you but I think I dance", "c": "Thank you but I think I write", "d": "Thank you but I think I draw" }, "correctAnswer": "c" }, { "question": "Siiri viulu on tuolin takana", "answers": { "a": "Siiri the baseball is behind the chair", "b": "Siiri the drums are behind the chair", "c": "Siiri the piano is behind the chair", "d": "Siiri the violin is behind the chair" }, "correctAnswer": "d" }];

const q2025Kappale5 = [{ question: "Vastaa englanniksi; Voiko Rambo ja Elli uida?", answers: { a: "No hey can not", b: "No they can't", c: "No they can can", d: "Yes hey can" }, "correctAnswer": "b"}, {question: "Vastaa englanniksi; Voiko Rambo hyppiä esteitä?", answers: { a: "No he cannu", b: "No she can't", c: "No she can nt", d: "Yes he can" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}, {"question": "Ratsastaako Elli Silverillä? Kysytään!", answers: { a: "Does Elli ride Silver? Let's ask!", b: "Do Elli hide Silver? Let's ask!", c: "Does Elli ride Silver? Let ask!", d: "Does Elli rade Silver? Let's ask!" }, "correctAnswer": "a"}, {"question":"Mikä oli Ellin hevosen nimi ?", answers: { a: "Hat was Elli's horse name?", b: "What was Ellis horses name?", c: "What is Elli's horse's name?", d: "What is Elli's horses name ? " }, "correctAnswer": "c"}, {"question":"Puhutaan sanoi Anni", answers: { a: "Get talk said Annu", b: "Let's go said Anni", c: "Let's shout said Anni", d: "Let's talk said Anni" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}, {"question": "Please Elli don't shout to Felix", answers: { a: "Pyydän Elli älä puhu Felixille", b: "Pyydän Elli älä huuda Felixille", c: "Pyydän Elli huuda Felixille", d: "Pyydän Elli älä painosta Felixiä" }, "correctAnswer": "b"}, {"question": "Tule Pompula, hypätään esteitä", answers: { a: "Come Pompula let's jump obstacles", b: "Go Pompula let's jump obstacles", c: "Come Pompula get jump obstacles", d: "Come Pompula let jump obstacles" }, "correctAnswer": "a"}, {"question": "Missä on Pompulan hevosenkenkä ? ", answers: { a: "Where is Pompula's hoseshoe? ", b: "Where is Pompula once horseshoe ? ", c: "Here is Pompula one horseshoe ? ", d: "Where is Pompula's horseshoe?" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}, {"question": "Cash ja minä - olemme melkein perillä", answers: { a: "Cash and I - we are almost there", b: "Cash and you we are almost here", c: "Cash and I let's go there", d: "Cash and me go to the stable we are almost there" }, "correctAnswer": "c"}, {"question":"Fiona pidätkö porkkanoista vai perunoista?", answers: { a: "Fiona do you like charriots or potatoes?", b: "Fiona you like cars or potatoes?", c: "Fiona do you like carrots or potatoes?", d: "Fiona like you carrots or potatoes" }, correctAnswer: "c"}]

const questions2025Vahan6Ja7 = [{"question": "Perttu sääntö on että älä potki hevosta", "answers": { "a": "Perttu role is that don’t kick the horse", "b": "Perttu the rule is that don’t kick the horse", "c": "Perttu role is that do kick the horse", "d": "Perttu rule is so don’t kick horse" }, "correctAnswer": "b"}, {"question": "Anna Mörököllille porkkana", "answers": { "a": "Give Mörökölli potatoes", "b": "Give Mörökölli a cookie", "c": "Give Mörökölli carrots", "d": "Give Mörökölli a carrot" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}, {"question": "Perttu anna salasana, kirjaudutaan ", "answers": { "a": "Perttu give the password let’s lo in", "b": "Perttu give the pasword let’s log in", "c": "Perttu give the password let’s log in", "d": "Perttu give password go log in" }, "correctAnswer": "c"}, {"question": "Nyt Rölli muista meidän salaisuus ", "answers": { "a": "Now Rölli remember the secret", "b": "Now Rölli remember out secret", "c": "Now Rölli remember our secret", "d": "Now Rölli rember our secret" }, "correctAnswer": "c"}, {"question": "Mufasi miten nimesi kirjoitetaan?", "answers": { "a": "Mufasi how you sell your name?", "b": "Mufasi how do we spell our name?", "c": "Mufasi well do you spell your name?", "d": "Mufasi how do you spell your name?" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}, {"question": "Rölli oletko vihainen syö kakkua", "answers": { "a": "Rölli are you sad eat the cale", "b": "Rölli are you bad eat the cake", "c": "Rölli are you mad eat the cake", "d": "Rölli are you nice wat the cake" }, "correctAnswer": "c"}, {"question": "Jorma tallenna Röllin kuva", "answers": { "a": "Jorma save Rölli’s picture", "b": "Jorma gave Rölli’s picture", "c": "Jorma same Rölli’s picture", "d": "Jorma get Rölli’s picture" }, "correctAnswer": "a"}, {"question": "Perttu muista lähettää netssä kuva", "answers": { "a": "Perttu rebeber to send picture online", "b": "Perttu remember to send the picture online", "c": "Perttu remember to bed the picture in internet", "d": "Perttu remmber to send the picture online" }, "correctAnswer": "b"}, {"question": "Perttu oletko ostoksilla?", "answers": { "a": "Perttu are you shoeing?", "b": "Perttu are thou thopping?", "c": "Perttu are you shopping?", "d": "Perttu are you topping?" }, "correctAnswer": "c"}, {"question": "Kyllä mikä tämä on mailako?", "answers": { "a": "Yes whas this a racket?", "b": "Yes what this a racket?", "c": "Yes what’s this a racet?", "d": "Yes what’s this a racket?" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}]

const questionsKappale58Koe1 = [{"question": "Volleyball", "answers": { "a": "Piiloleikki", "b": "Pesäpallo", "c": "Salibandy", "d": "Lentopallo" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}, {"question": "Hide-and-seek", "answers": { "a": "Salibandy", "b": "Piiloleikki", "c": "Ruutuhyppely", "d": "Hippa" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}, {"question": "Tag", "answers": { "a": "Salibandy", "b": "Ruutuhyppely", "c": "Pesäpallo", "d": "Hippa" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}, {"question": "Cards", "answers": { "a": "Piilokeikki", "b": "Pesäpallo", "c": "Korttipelit", "d": "Videopelit" }, "correctAnswer": "c"}, {"question": "Pesäpallo", "answers": { "a": "Cards", "b": "Baseball", "c": "Video Games", "d": "Cash" }, "correctAnswer": "b"}, {"question": "Sulkapallo", "answers": { "a": "Badminton", "b": "Baseball", "c": "Hopscotch", "d": "Goodminton" }, "correctAnswer": "a"}, {"question": "Floor ball", "answers": { "a": "Lattiapallo", "b": "Piilopallo", "c": "Piiloleikki", "d": "Salibandy" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}, {"question": "Table tennis", "answers": { "a": "Pöytäliina", "b": "Pöytätennis", "c": "Ruokapöytä", "d": "Tennis pöytä" }, "correctAnswer": "b"}, {"question": "Shakki", "answers": { "a": "Chess", "b": "Salibandy", "c": "Pesäpallo", "d": "Ruutuhyppely" }, "correctAnswer": "a"}, {"question": "Videopelit", "answers": { "a": "Hop Games", "b": "Tag", "c": "Tennis", "d": "Video games" }, "correctAnswer": "d"}]

